[{"id": "59ca3dc444f0f6af5b06663f", "question": "Andorra la Vella is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Andorra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e6", "question": "What actor was born with the name Tadewurz Konopka?", "answer": "Ted Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b738", "question": "Tennis player Margaret Smith Court who holds a record 62 Grand Slam titles is from which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f97", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab6", "question": "What is the first name of the drummer for the band Van Halen?", "answer": "Alex", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd82165d0de9af39e9d46a5", "question": "As of 2020, who is the longest serving Chief Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "John Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b109", "question": "What city hosted the 1992 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7be6a877e98cb9777895f", "question": "What continent contains the most fresh water?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51bc9ff04d658268c9310", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66942a5bfecdd737e0879", "question": "Why do Italians eat lentils on New Year's Eve?", "answer": "To bring good fortune", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339328", "question": "In \"The Matrix\", what color pill did Neo take?", "answer": "The red pill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fc", "question": "Who played Ashley Judd's husband in the 1999 movie \"Double Jeopardy\"?", "answer": "Bruce Greenwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a886", "question": "The word \"serendipity\" comes from Serendip, the Persian name for what island?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc1", "question": "Which of David Bowie's eyes has a permanently dilated pupil?", "answer": "Left", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e053fe83fe1f2a824b8a", "question": "What country held its first democratic elections on January 30, 2005?", "answer": "Iraq", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a476", "question": "What African country was formerly known as Northern Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09b", "question": "What is the fear of knowledge known as?", "answer": "Epistemophobia or gnosiophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4d", "question": "An Apgar score is given to what?", "answer": "Health of newborns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c1", "question": "What nationality was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor E. Frankl?", "answer": "Austrian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51862ff04d658268c92ff", "question": "What is the most number of years a U.S. president can serve?", "answer": "Ten years -- two years from a previous president's election plus two four-year terms. This is based on the 22nd Amendment.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990af76b72eedf883a8c707", "question": "Which US state was nicknamed \"Old Dominion\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89c", "question": "How long, in yards, is an NFL football field?", "answer": "100 -- The playing field is 100 yards. However, when the end zones are included, the entire field is 120 yards.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c457", "question": "Whose \"Difference Engine\" is often described as the first computer?", "answer": "Charles Babbage's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6dc", "question": "What do sumo wrestlers call their hair topknots?", "answer": "Chonmage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904f", "question": "Who composed \"Peter and the Wolf\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cc", "question": "What cards do you have if you have a \"Big Slick\" in the game \"Texas Hold 'Em\"?", "answer": "An ace and a king of the same suit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922e", "question": "Who stars in the semi-autobiographical movie \"Purple Rain\"?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595245b7736d4be723796b6e", "question": "The tiles used in which game have dots that are called \"Pips\"?", "answer": "Dominoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d06", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Pedro Sanchez?", "answer": "Napoleon Dynamite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ae", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe735d0eec85e375820b252", "question": "Who was the architect of Operation Market Garden?", "answer": "General Bernard Montgomery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0a", "question": "What was President Truman's first name?", "answer": "Harry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d47103f8e329de4f877897", "question": "What is the brewery featured in the British soap opera \"Coronation Street\"?", "answer": "Newton and Ridley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f8", "question": "Which actress played Forrest Gump's mom?", "answer": "Sally Field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffdce1cf6db9ac4808d0a", "question": "What is the largest city by area in the continental United States?", "answer": "Sitka, Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded288ea2747c8aff16d3e", "question": "What year did Dwight D. Eisenhower publish his autobiography titled \"Crusade in Europe\"?", "answer": "1948", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a809", "question": "What US state capital city lies at the western edge of its state's Bluegrass Region?", "answer": "Frankfort", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339147", "question": "What year did Pinocchio first appear in published media?", "answer": "1883", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c692", "question": "A nebula is a large interstellar cloud of what?", "answer": "Dust and gases", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Anthony Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6f", "question": "What Nirvana and Smashing Pumpkins record produced later became the drummer in Garbage?", "answer": "Butch Vig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b4", "question": "The VIC-20 and PET were personal computers manufactured by which company?", "answer": "Commodore International, Ltd.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8bc5ec223966ae8f8842", "question": "Dr. Gregory House shares the same home address as which other fictional character?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes (albeit in different countries)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a9dc9bff04efae6d761", "question": "From which country did the US buy the United States Virgin Islands in 1916?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b99", "question": "Who is the main character in the Odyssey?", "answer": "Odysseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ce", "question": "What are the names of the Pep Boys?", "answer": "Manny, Moe, and Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774305284458f1d7854424", "question": "Who was the first host of \"America's Got Talent\"?", "answer": "Regis Philbin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7d", "question": "What constitutional amendment established prohibition in the US?", "answer": "18th Constitutional Amendment", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b69", "question": "What was the first sports-themed movie to win the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Rocky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774295284458f1d7854421", "question": "What contestant-based reality television series aired in the United States originated in Holland?", "answer": "The Voice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ac8e01dd7bf43be5e76d", "question": "Succulent is derived from the Latin word \"sucus\", meaning what?", "answer": "Sap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8793ec223966ae8f8816", "question": "Which year did American legendary golfer, Tiger Woods win his first Masters Tournament?", "answer": "1997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b349", "question": "Who was the first woman to sail single-handed around the world?", "answer": "Naomi James", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ea16b24f84e0b9f9ffcf", "question": "What group sang the theme song to the TV show \"Square Pegs\"?", "answer": "The Waitresses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd03", "question": "It is sometimes considered a fashion faux pas to wear white after what holiday?", "answer": "Labor Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cbd7bb53d1af658864dc", "question": "What holiday is celebrated on December 26th in Canada?", "answer": "Boxing Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93a6f6bd93ce3a4e5f697", "question": "Who is \"the Science Guy\"?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a4", "question": "Which is the most densely populated country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab6", "question": "What is the more common name for Cerumen?", "answer": "Earwax", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b794", "question": "In skiing, what is a mogul?", "answer": "A bump or small hill", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589675db0d66a186cb54b", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067b3eff9c0647b50a8062", "question": "With what global issue does the 2016 Paris Agreement deal with?", "answer": "Climate change", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febbcde7e83c707845b2152", "question": "Who played Dracula in the 1931 vampire-horror film \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd1", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Melanion defeat in a footrace?", "answer": "Atalanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f0d26682715b82711cda", "question": "What does the saying \"Requiescat in pace\" abbreviate to?", "answer": "RIP", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72ceb5d0874f1a5e2d1c28", "question": "What country borders both North Korea and Finland?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc991d875534e0fe3fe3c2b", "question": "Who said, \"I don't like to pay for the same real estate twice\"?", "answer": "General George S Patton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998f", "question": "What year was the movie \"Star Trek: The Motion Picture\" released?", "answer": "1979", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f60", "question": "What supermodel plays the bride in Guns N' Roses' \"November Rain\" video?", "answer": "Stephanie Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a3c01dd7bf43be5e898", "question": "An octopus can fit through any hole larger than its what?", "answer": "Its beak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a487cf93664eb10486c4", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", where did David and Katchoo first meet?", "answer": "In a museum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b600", "question": "What US state was the home of General Motors' original \"Saturn\" automobile plant?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85e", "question": "Which European country is often referred to as the \"Battlefield of Europe\"?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a5", "question": "What is the Japanese name for Japan?", "answer": "Nippon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc1573469bb8041d07a08b", "question": "What London landmark did Queen Elizabeth II open up to tourism in 1993?", "answer": "Buckingham Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995c", "question": "Who were the two villains in the movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "The Penguin and Catwoman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9b", "question": "What is the family name of the creator of Tobasco sauce?", "answer": "McIllhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6d", "question": "What sports figure was known as \"The Wizard of Westwood\"?", "answer": "John Wooden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323343bf195a31e15d739a", "question": "Gaborone is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8db", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Volta river?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf5", "question": "In what city did Anne Frank write her diary?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab149fbaab681b09292176", "question": "What year did GM first introduce the Corvette?", "answer": "1953", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ff", "question": "What is the name of the Austrian Monk who formulated the basic laws of genetics?", "answer": "Gregor Mendel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ed", "question": "What are the four largest islands in Canada?", "answer": "Baffin, Victoria, Ellesmere and Newfoundland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10e", "question": "What type of alcoholic drink is Manzanilla?", "answer": "Sherry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1b31f6756c9b30ba14f6", "question": "On which river is the city of Mandalay situated?", "answer": "Irrawaddy River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3cefff048f679a45ab44", "question": "Which animal can cause a tularemia infection in humans while being skinned for cooking purposes?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c160", "question": "Mageirocophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Having to cook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1a", "question": "What is the colour of mourning in Turkey?", "answer": "Violet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989ad41cb8751d53e7d760f", "question": "An 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland,share what name?", "answer": "Kindred Spirits", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d1", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Cump\"?", "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb2", "question": "What disease killed 20,000 Parisians in 1832?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a046", "question": "What is the name of the town where the Sons of Anarchy have their motorcycle club?", "answer": "Charming, California", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5922067da4edfd43a087adee", "question": "In which Arthur Miller play does Willy Loman feature?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13e", "question": "In the first Punic War, Rome and Carthage fought over possession of what Mediterranean island?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc63", "question": "What year saw the release of the first Hot Wheels toy car?", "answer": "1968", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339654", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Fat Tony's establishment?", "answer": "The Legitimate Businessmen's Social Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe738e8eec85e375820b26a", "question": "Where is the USA's first ski town located?", "answer": "Woodstock, Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f9", "question": "What martial art's name means \"way of the sword\"?", "answer": "Kendo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac65", "question": "What name was Eva Peron known by?", "answer": "Evita", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e87f06d333868d34d749", "question": "What US state was the first to require license plates?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf1", "question": "The month July is named for what historical leader?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a2", "question": "Who authored 1883's \"The Adventures of Pinocchio\"?", "answer": "Carlo Collodi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd52", "question": "The Juno Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Canadian music", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66f", "question": "Washington D.C. is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Potomac River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c764", "question": "What was the name of the IBM supercomputer which defeated chess champion Garry Kasparov in a 1997 match?", "answer": "Deep Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f8abfa5fdd6dd25324f0", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what comic book series did Comic Book Guy create?", "answer": "Everyman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c306", "question": "Which is longer, a python or a boa constrictor?", "answer": "A python", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a127cf93664eb10486bd", "question": "Jurgen Rumor, a former professional soccer player, hails from what European country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eec", "question": "El Greco painted a famous View of what Spanish city?", "answer": "Toledo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1f", "question": "In golf, what is the traditional name for a number 3 wood?", "answer": "Spoon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efe", "question": "What famous horse belonged to The Lone Ranger?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdc91e347d002c297e4e9", "question": "In 1973 Roland Ohisson was buried in a coffin made of what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba3", "question": "What was Karen Allen's character's name in \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Marion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995e", "question": "What was the name of Fred Sanford\u2019s late wife on the TV show \"Sanford & Son\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee0", "question": "What literary villain died during a struggle at Reichenbach Falls?", "answer": "Professor Moriarty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb43", "question": "What is the only bonus item, that dances around the maze, Ms. Pac-Man can eat that is not a type of fruit?", "answer": "Pretzel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a5525f3e1c6f9840ba3194", "question": "Where was the Armistice, between the Allies and Germany, signed on November 11, 1918?", "answer": "Compiegne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbf7c003d27d341092bd7", "question": "Which is the only country to have its own official scent?", "answer": "Lithuania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe7", "question": "What is the name of Stephen Hawking's cosmology book published In 1988?", "answer": "A Brief History Of Time", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d6", "question": "How many yards are there in a mile?", "answer": "1760", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f7", "question": "In the movie \"Some Like It Hot\", who played the role of Sugar Kane Kowalczyk?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ec2f06d333868d34d761", "question": "In which year was the White Australia Policy formally abolished?", "answer": "1972", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba35", "question": "What brand of whiskey is made in Lynchburg, Tennessee?", "answer": "Jack Daniels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c90ffbde8045e48466e7", "question": "Which farm animal mates for life?", "answer": "Geese are among the most faithful animals. Once they choose a partner, they mate for life. They even mourn when a partner dies.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad7d", "question": "Which enemy of the Roman Empire was nicknamed the \"Scourge of God\" by the Catholic Church?", "answer": "Attila the Hun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd99", "question": "How many points is the red inner circle on a dartboard bull's-eye worth?", "answer": "Fifty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d3", "question": "Who played the role of Tracy Samantha Lord in the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61b", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Lead?", "answer": "Pb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fbae8510738315b1fb74e28", "question": "What is the only major city located on two continents?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa3f16ce05a3942286ead", "question": "Which national monument does Cary Grant climb in \"North by Northwest\"?", "answer": "Mount Rushmore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb085dacf631c2414a13b4f", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what is Chandler\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Muriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11c", "question": "Which Greek island was the center of the Minoan civilization?", "answer": "Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16814f7c52aae91cc07c2", "question": "Which opera singer was known as \"La Stupenda\"?", "answer": "Joan Sutherland", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c011", "question": "Sakhmet was the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War and healing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba18c874c93a3298b2127", "question": "Of which US state was Jimmy Carter Governor before he became president?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfa", "question": "What's the meat in McDonald's original recipe for Egg McMuffins?", "answer": "Canadian bacon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a524", "question": "Red Lake is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88c", "question": "The seismic belt called the Ring of Fire surrounds what body of water?", "answer": "The Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab9", "question": "Sauerbraten is a specialty beef dish that originated in what country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Alabama?", "answer": "Montgomery", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9d", "question": "Who was the last king of Troy killed by Achilles son Pyrrhus?", "answer": "Priam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04c", "question": "The Treaty of Versailles officially ended what major war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b50201dd7bf43be5e7cb", "question": "What is the main ingredient in the British dish laverbread?", "answer": "Seaweed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338879", "question": "What is the literary term for a play on words?", "answer": "Pun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e86", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Centaur?", "answer": "Human and horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c5", "question": "What is the longest running US game show?", "answer": "Price is Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929b", "question": "On the TV series \"Lost\", what is John Locke incapable of doing before Oceanic flight 815 crashes?", "answer": "Walking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b9", "question": "What comedic duo starred in the movie \"Stir Crazy\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder and Richard Pryor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77cf2f24f0f7a362efd54c", "question": "How many claws in total does the average adult cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c244", "question": "How many sides does a hexagon have?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937b", "question": "In the movie \"The Godfather\", where was Santino Corleone gunned down?", "answer": "At a toll booth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d91", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Sabotage\" based on?", "answer": "The Secret Agent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4a92c6c6b019850c9a77", "question": "What fruit did Native Americans use to treat arrow wounds and to dye clothes?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b381", "question": "Who had to be removed for swearing from President Andrew Jackson's funeral?", "answer": "His Pet Parrot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83e", "question": "What 2 articles of clothing are tokens in the standard Monopoly game?", "answer": "Shoe and Top Hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8da", "question": "Who became head of the Chrysler Corporation in 1978?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa551cc73aa70ea0b70b21", "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?", "answer": "Akihabara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3f", "question": "What is a gondola?", "answer": "Venetian rowing boat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fb", "question": "Which is the biggest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a3", "question": "Before the vowel shift of the middle ages, how would the English pronounce \"Mickey Mouse\"?", "answer": "Mickey Moose", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c945", "question": "Kr is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Krypton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe937d86bd93ce3a4e5f679", "question": "Gynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Women", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d3", "question": "What is the Latin name for the atmospheric glow also called the \"southern lights\"?", "answer": "Aurora australis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8af2a01dd7bf43be5e788", "question": "How much of the population is left-handed?", "answer": "10%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fb", "question": "What vitamin complex includes thiamine, niacin and riboflavin?", "answer": "Vitamin B", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe4", "question": "What colony was established by the passengers of the Mayflower?", "answer": "Plymouth Colony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339175", "question": "Who voices Darth Vader in the original Star Wars movies?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2a", "question": "What familiar product is Rich Uncle Pennybags the mascot for?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c3", "question": "What would be scored by the Apgar score?", "answer": "Health of newborns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7c", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Power of Positive Thinking\"?", "answer": "Norman Vincent Peale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69f9120565ad31a57c78d", "question": "What sport\u2019s first non-military competition was hosted in Norway in 1868?", "answer": "Downhill skiing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdff66a1cf6db9ac4808cee", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest sea?", "answer": "Australasian Mediterranean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d08181a1c922dd1ac64bf", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338894", "question": "What did Rumpelstiltskin spin into gold?", "answer": "Straw", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b9", "question": "In 1901, William McKinley was assassinated in which US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e5", "question": "What were 2 out of 3 of Andrew Lloyd Webbers wives called?", "answer": "Sarah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2d", "question": "Captain James Cook made how many voyages to the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "3", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c258", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation CPU stand for?", "answer": "Central Processing Unit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a289", "question": "The Heavy Young Heathens cover \"The House of the Rising Sun\" on the soundtrack of which 2016 remake?", "answer": "The Magnificent Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a059", "question": "\"Run\" is a 1994 Hong Kong remake of which shoe string-budget action film by Robert Rodriguez?", "answer": "El Mariachi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de0", "question": "What former musician played bass on Madonna's \"Like a Prayer\"?", "answer": "Randy Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d119214fea7fe947a2228b", "question": "Which song from The Beatles' the \"White Album\" was originally entitled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aebc", "question": "Which member of British royal family has the extra Christian names Anthony Richard Louis?", "answer": "Prince Edward", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ed", "question": "Which band produced the mega selling album \"Rumours\"?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1746682715b82711ce0", "question": "Amor Vincit Omnia a Latin phrase meaning what?", "answer": "Love conquers all", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c8", "question": "Over its 7 season run, how many episodes of the TV show \"30 Rock\" were aired?", "answer": "138", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b358", "question": "What was the real name of the Boston Strangler?", "answer": "Albert DeSalvo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc9", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional band \"Drive Shaft\"?", "answer": "Lost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399df", "question": "In the 1991 animated Disney film \"Beauty and the Beast\", what type of enchanted item is Chip?", "answer": "A teacup", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc144d469bb8041d07a086", "question": "What is mistletoe used for according to Polish folklore?", "answer": "Ward off evil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96ae623c87fd04dd15e16", "question": "Jeans are named for what European city?", "answer": "Genoa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af9858caeb0982ee455954e", "question": "Which physical force is the only one that is always attractive, never repulsive?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f0", "question": "Which continent is the home of the tsetse fly?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c60", "question": "What liqueur was Vincent Van Gogh said to be heavily drinking heavily the night he cut off his ear?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07e", "question": "What model of automatic rifle was the most commonly used by American soldiers in South Vietnam?", "answer": "M-16", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c5", "question": "What are the three main sections of an insect's body?", "answer": "The head, the abdomen and the thorax", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e5ebfe83fe1f2a824bc7", "question": "Which medieval queen was married to both Louis VII of France and Henry II of England?", "answer": "Eleanor of Aquitaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c7", "question": "What is the Latin name for a guinea pig?", "answer": "Caviaprocellus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe378a40ada16518afdc052", "question": "Which President's library has their actual Air Force One Boeing 707 on display?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43b", "question": "What year did Albert Einstein die?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae33", "question": "When did the War of 1812 actually begin?", "answer": "1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d0", "question": "What was the last desktop computer made by Commodore?", "answer": "The Amiga 4000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8beeec223966ae8f8845", "question": "The protagonist in \"Grand Theft Auto: Vice City\" was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2d", "question": "What date is inscribed in the tablet held by the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "July 4, 1776", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70c85f96e155acab35d2d", "question": "Which country suffered the most casualties in World War II?", "answer": "Soviet Union", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf0", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of The Sad Cafe\"?", "answer": "Carson McCullers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbe546ce05a3942286eed", "question": "Which actor had a role in the Hannibal Lector films \"Manhunter,\" \"Silence of the Lambs,\" \"Hannibal\" and \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Frankie Faison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c558", "question": "What is the common name for \"graphospasm\"?", "answer": "Writer's cramp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea782dff048f679a45abd4", "question": "If a doctor told you there was fluid entering your lungs, what term might he use to describe this?", "answer": "Aspiration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b774", "question": "Brigham Young was a leader of which religious group?", "answer": "Mormons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe0", "question": "What was the name of Juliet's cousin killed by Benvolio in \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Tybalt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e448fe83fe1f2a824bb0", "question": "What was the location of the second major Allied assault into Europe in 1944?", "answer": "The attack of the French Mediterranean coast", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29a", "question": "What planet has the shortest year?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d55952800b05cac20f1d", "question": "During what geological time period did the T-Rex roam the Earth?", "answer": "Cretaceous Period", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51b04ff04d658268c930b", "question": "What kind of man-eating monster did Odysseus blind?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac6", "question": "What is the capital of of the US state of Indiana?", "answer": "Indianapolis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b89", "question": "What is the number of thieves that Alibaba had?", "answer": "40", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067fbfff9c0647b50a8087", "question": "Overall, how many medals did US swimmer Michael Phelps win at the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c874", "question": "European bees were bred with bees from what other continent to create \"killer\" bees?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b663", "question": "Which automaker sold a car model named \"Colt\"?", "answer": "Dodge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339630", "question": "Which TV show's theme song starts with the words \"Come and knock on my door...\"?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339490", "question": "Anthony Hopkins played a ventriloquist in which 1978 movie?", "answer": "Magic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea37f3ff048f679a45ab1e", "question": "What is it called when you make light change direction by passing it through a lens?", "answer": "Refraction", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c9", "question": "Who voices Homer Simpson in the TV show \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Dan Castellaneta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173c3444491cbd7c5a17a4", "question": "What collectively-named languages evolved from Vulgar Latin?", "answer": "Romance or romanic language -- The five most spoken romance languages are Spanish, French, Portuguese, Italian and Romanian.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a612", "question": "Which is the third largest Caribbean island?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8ac8101dd7bf43be5e76c", "question": "Which common houseplant is said to make burns heal faster?", "answer": "Aloe Vera", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70cd5f96e155acab35d2f", "question": "What country once technically fought a war against a species of bird?", "answer": "Australia, \"The Emu War\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b548", "question": "What day is hump day?", "answer": "Wednesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48b", "question": "In which city is the Prado art gallery located?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b391", "question": "Who won the first Boat Race between Oxford and Cambridge?\u00a0", "answer": "Oxford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc1", "question": "Where do fallen Norse warriors go?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe37a5f0ada16518afdc058", "question": "What two countries declared war on Germany after it invaded Poland?", "answer": "Great Britain and France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec26928dc25ca9e12ef64d", "question": "How many engines does the B-52 bomber have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bdb", "question": "Which author won the Booker Prize 1986 for the novel \"The Old Devils\"?", "answer": "Kingsley Amis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c495", "question": "What vitamin group is mostly required for blood coagulation?", "answer": "Vitamin K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3f", "question": "Juba is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339202", "question": "What do Brad Pitt and Edward Norton shoot at factories while drunk in \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Golf Balls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73e84eec85e375820b275", "question": "Which U.S. Lake has its own version of the Bermuda Triangle?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c6", "question": "What year did Edward Jenner introduce the world's first successful vaccine?", "answer": "1796", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47c", "question": "What is a small group of islands called?", "answer": "Archipelago", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5952413d736d4be723796b61", "question": "Which superhero was created by Mike Young, as a way to help his child sleep at night?", "answer": "SuperTed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b7", "question": "The Columbia River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d089bb53d1af658864fc", "question": "What year did the Trans-Siberian Orchestra release their debut album entitled \"Christmas Eve and Other Stories\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96a7423c87fd04dd15e12", "question": "As of 2020, which astronaut had spent the most time in space?", "answer": "Gennady Padalka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339117", "question": "What year did H. G. Wells publish \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "1896", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddaec6ce05a3942286d8a", "question": "Which videogame console did Nintendo release directly prior to the Wii?", "answer": "The GameCube, released in 2001, was the predecessor to the Wii.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff1", "question": "Who wrote the \"Noddy\" books?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c58cfbde8045e48466af", "question": "Vultures gathering on the side of the road, feeding on a carcass, are called what?", "answer": "Vulture groups have different terms depending on their behavior. When they are feeding on a carcass, they are called a wake.", "category": "science"}]